The fight to save the world is on!
Street Fighter is a action, adventure, comedy film
directed by Steven E. de Souza.
Colonel Guile and various other martial arts heroes
fight against the tyranny of dictator M.
Bison and his cohorts.
Colonel Guile, played by Jean-Claude Van Damme.
Bison, played by Raúl Juliá.
Cammy, played by Kylie Minogue.
Ryu, played by Byron Mann.
Ken, played by Damian Chapa.
Chun-Li, played by Ming-Na Wen.
Street Fighter is a 1994 martial arts action film
written and directed by Steven E.
de Souza, based on the video game series of the same
name developed and published by Capcom.
It was one of two films released in 1994 specifically adapting Street
Fighter II, following Street Fighter II: The Animated Movie.
Distributed by Universal Pictures in the United States and Canada; and Columbia Pictures through Columbia TriStar Film Distributors International internationally, the film stars
Jean-Claude Van Damme and Raul Julia (in his final theatrical film role) along with supporting performances by Byron Mann, Damian Chapa, Kylie Minogue, Ming-Na Wen and Wes Studi.
The adaptation focuses on the efforts by Colonel Guile
(Van Damme) to bring down General M.
Bison (Julia), the military dictator and drug kingpin of Shadaloo City who aspires to conquer the world with an army of genetic supersoldiers,
while enlisting the aid of street fighters Ryu (Mann) and Ken (Chapa) to infiltrate Bison's empire and help destroy it from within.
The film was commercially successful, with a worldwide box office
gross approximately three times its production costs.
Home video releases and television broadcasts were also profitable.
While it earned Capcom a return of ¥15.5 billion ($165 million) from the box office and home media, it was poorly
received by critics and fans for its campy tone, unfaithfulness to the source material, and overblown effects.
However, Julia's performance as M.
Bison was singled out for widespread critical acclaim and garnered him a posthumous nomination for Best
Supporting Actor at the Saturn Awards, and the film has since developed as a cult classic.
The film was Julia's final theatrical performance, as he died of a stroke two
months before the film's release; the film is dedicated to his memory.
The film explores themes of martial arts, hostage,
liberation of hostage, dictator, hostage-taking.
The tone is lighthearted and intense.